so let us try our hand at computing some
reliability and availability suppose
that the system we are considering is
just a hard disk and this disk we buy it
we put it in our machine and now it
works fine for 12 months and then it
breaks because it cannot spin anymore
and then it takes us one month to
replace the motor in the disk and after
that fix it works fine for about four
months and then it breaks again and we
find that the problem is that it cannot
move heads and it took us two months to
figure that out and then get the heads
on stock and now the disk works fine for
14 months and then it breaks and we find
that the head has broken and we find
this quickly but then realize it to take
us three months to fix it so we throw
this disk away and buy a new one so the
questions for you or what is the MTTF
for this disk what is the mttr for this
disk and what is the availability of
this disk expressed as a percentage